I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
even though I love you so much
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
You said we should break up
Mou wakareyou to
Kimi no koe ga kikoeta shunkan
and when I heard that
my world turned white in an instant
Mou masshiro ni natte
Karadajuu ni hashitta hibana
and sparks danced in my vision
Is forgetting you what I need
Kimi no koto wo wasureru koto ga
Mae ni susundeku koto na no?
to move on?
I could cry now, I don't understand
Wakaranai yo nakete kuru yo
Let's live in the moment, only in the moment
Seiippai meiippai ima wo ikiyou
We lived like that until now, too, I guess
Sou yatte ikite kita kedo
I couldn't say goodbye
Ienai ienai sayonara nante
Konna ni daisuki na no ni
even though I love you so much
(愛花･回想)((今夜は
花火が きれいに見えそうですね))
Looks like we'll have a good view of the fireworks tonight.
Yeah...
(滝川吉野)((そうだね))
((あのさ➡
So...
I heard that when you wear a yukata,
浴衣のときは
ラインが出ないように➡
you don't wear underwear to avoid panty lines...
下着を着けないって
聞いたことあるけど 本当？))
Is that true?
(愛花)((上は着けていません｡
下は秘密です))
I'm not wearing a top.
The bottom half is a secret.
(愛花)((しかし➡
However,
if you have an uncontrollable desire to know,
どうしても知りたいという
熱烈な欲望があるのなら➡
I shall allow you to reach in and see for yourself, Yoshino.
吉野さんが じかに手を差し入れて
確かめるのを許可しますが))
((あっ！ えっと…➡
Uh...
I'm really sorry!
ごめんなさい！
くだらないことを聞きました！))
I asked something totally stupid!
((まあ 意気地のないことですね))
No backbone whatsoever.
((やっぱり
愛花ちゃん 性格悪いよね))
You really do have a terrible personality, Aika.
((そういう吉野さんこそ➡
And are you claiming that you
are such a virtuous person yourself, Yoshino?
自分を善良な人間と
言い張る気ですか？))
I guess I can't say that, considering that I'm dating Aika
(心の声)≪そりゃ 真広に隠れて
愛花ちゃんとつきあっていて➡
behind Mahiro's back.
善良とは言えないだろうけど…≫
((バン！ バン！))
((バン！))
(愛花)((私が知る中で➡
Out of everyone that I know,
I believe you are the most frightening, Yoshino.
吉野さんが
いちばん怖い人だと思いますよ？))
Episode 16
The Wandering Apparition
(潤一郎)((葉風ちゃんが
吉野君との関係を強く望むなら…))
If you were to desire a relationship with Yoshino strongly enough,
the Tree of Genesis would kill that girlfriend.
(潤一郎)((その彼女
はじまりの樹に殺されるよ))
(葉風)≪私が関係を強く望む？≫
If I were to desire it strongly enough?
Inconceivable.
≪ありえん｡ 別に私は
吉野と こうしているだけで…≫
Besides, I'm totally content to spend time with Yoshino like this—
≪そもそも それがいかんのか!?≫
That must be where I'm going wrong!
Are you listening, Miss Hakaze?
聞いてます？ 葉風さん｡
Oh! D-Did you say something?
(葉風)
うおっ！ なっ 何か言ったか？
I was saying that a spy has apparently infiltrated the Kusaribe village.
ですから 鎖部の村に 諜報員が
入ったらしいって話ですけど｡
(葉風)あっ ああ～ そうだったな｡
O-Oh, right...
But why would Yamamoto have that information?
しかし
山本が なぜ そんな情報を…｡
She must be after something.
何か狙いがありそうだ｡
えっ？
It's starting.
≪始まるぞ！
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ](ﾘﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)皆さん あちらが➡
Everyone,
Only Moments Until the Event!?
this is the tree marked for destruction by the self-named mage of Exodus.
絶園の魔法使いを名乗る人物が
破壊を予告した樹です｡➡
Only Moments Until the Event!?
It's almost time,
予告時刻は迫っていますが
まだ 周囲に変化は見られません｡
but there have been no visible changes so far.
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)これで いたずらだったら
つまらないですよねぇ｡
This will really suck if it's a prank.
(ﾃﾞｨﾚｸﾀｰ)
どうも本物っぽいんだよ｡➡
But it seems to be the real deal.
予告で あの樹のこと
はじまりの樹と呼称されてたろ｡➡
In the announcement, didn't he claim that tree was a "Tree of Genesis"?
That is the true name of that Tree,
その呼び方
政府でも ごく一部しか知らない➡
known only by a few in the government.
あの樹の正式名称だそうだ｡
えっ？
Hey!
おい！
あれは!?
That's...
(ﾘﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)なっ なんでしょう？➡
Wh-Who are they?
Could those two be mages of Exodus?
あの二人が
絶園の魔法使いなのでしょうか？
おい！ なんだ あれ!?
Hey, what's that?
あ… 新たに
魔法使いと思われる人影が➡
One more figure, believed to be a mage, has appeared before the Tree.
樹の前に現れました！➡
This footage has not been altered in any way!
映像には
何も手を加えていません！➡
Mysterious "Mage" Appears! Is This as Announced!?
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ] 本当に魔法のようです！
It truly is like magic.
(羽村)絶て｡
Eradicate!
(ﾘﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)ほっ 本当です！
本物の魔法使いです！➡
It's true! It's a real mage!
As announced, he appeared before us...
予告どおり 私たちの前に…｡
≫あっ！
見ろ！
(ﾘﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)あっ 魔法使いが空へ…➡
The mage is flying away into the sky!
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ] かなたへ飛んでいきます！
しかし 派手に…｡
(葉風)戻るぞ｡
That was so flashy.
We're heading back.
えっ？ ちょっと待ってください｡
Hey, wait a second...
予約したホテルの場所…｡
(葉風)そうではない｡➡
The hotel we reser—
That's not what I meant.
I'm saying we're going back to the Kusaribe stronghold.
鎖部の里に戻ると言っているのだ｡
えっ？
Huh?
If it's true that a spy has infiltrated the village, I cannot leave the matter alone.
(葉風)諜報員とやらが
入り込んだという話が誠なら➡
放ってもおけん｡
でも 何か狙いがあるかもって…｡
But you said they might be after something.
だから 逆に確かめたくなる｡
それが私の性分だ｡
All the more reason I wish to investigate.
That is my nature.
それに…｡
それに？
Besides...
Besides?
Forget it!
なんでもない！
あっ 葉風さん｡ あっ…｡
Ms. Hakaz—
≪里に帰って
頭を冷やしたいだけだ≫
I just want to go back home and cool off.
Not bad for such a wimp.
(不破真広)あの小心者にしちゃ
上出来だったな｡
(左門)失敗しても
周囲に被害が出ないよう➡
We chose a Tree that was relatively inaccessible to bystanders
to minimize collateral damage in case he messed up.
近づきにくい場所の樹を
選んだのだ｡➡
If he's intimidated now, we have a long road ahead.
これで おじけづかれては
先が大変だぞ｡
I wonder if he understands what's going to happen.
あいつ これからどうなるか➡
理解してやがるかな？
We'll be looking forward to another appearance by the mage!
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ](ﾘﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)
もう一度 魔法使いの登場を！➡
Back to you in the studio, Mr. Satake!
スタジオの佐竹さん！
(山本)お疲れ｡ 無事成功のようね｡
Good job.
Looks like everything went well.
(羽村)ぷは～！
しっ しっ 心臓が
口から飛び出しそうです！
I feel like my heart is going to explode!
Did we really have to do something that extreme?
大丈夫だったんですか？
あんな大げさなことして｡
まだ序の口よ｡
だんだんと派手にしていくから｡
We only just got started!
We'll make it even flashier next time.
There's gonna be more?
ちょっ！ まだやるんすか!?
国内は あと２か所｡
There are two other places in the country,
それから 海外｡
海外!?
and then we'll go overseas.
Overseas?!
はぁ～ 早く帰りたい…｡
I wanna go home.
Too bad.
残念だけどね
もう一つ ミッションが残ってるの｡
We have another mission.
(羽村)ええ～!?
(山本)大丈夫よ 君は眠ってて｡
Don't worry! You can get some sleep.
What about food? What about a bath?
(羽村)ご飯は!? お風呂は!?
≫(村人)姫様だ！
(佐奈)ん？
It's the princess!
The princess is back!
(村人)
姫様が戻ってこられたぞ～！
I knew I wouldn't die before seeing you again.
(老婆)帰って来るまで
死ねんと思うとったわ｡
(葉風)皆も元気で何よりだ｡
(ﾐｷ ﾋﾛﾕｷ)姫様～！
It's good to see you all doing well.
Princess!
You two have grown so much, Hiroyuki and Miki.
(葉風)おおっ ヒロユキ ミキも｡
すっかり大きくなって｡
(ﾋﾛﾕｷ)姫様 魔法で
男を引っ掛けてきたのか？
Did you get yourself a guy through magic, Princess?
You brat! What are you...
バカ！ 何を…｡
≫(佐奈)姫様～！
Princess!
ん？ 佐奈！
Sana!
(葉風)元気になったなぁ 佐奈｡
うん｡
You look a lot better, Sana.
お兄さんの墓？
Her brother's grave?
About six months before I was sent to the island, he lost his life
(葉風)私が島に送られる
半年ほど前だったか➡
病でな…｡
すこぶる仲のいい兄妹だったから➡
to an illness.
They were very close, so when he died,
she wouldn't get out of bed.
この子まで
ショックで寝込んでしまって｡
But she seems better now.
でも もう すっかり…｡
Indeed.
ああ 時が癒やしてくれたようだ｡
It appears that time healed her wounds.
Now that I'm back,
(葉風)
２年たったのだなと 改めて思う➡
I can clearly see that two years have passed.
ここに来るとな｡
(山本)狙いどおり運んだものね｡
To think she'd fall for it so easily...
You're the one who prepared the bait.
(哲馬)
誘いをかけたのは あんただろ｡
That's because Mr. Samon requested it.
だって
左門さんに頼まれたから…｡
So, we brought those two here
ねえ あの二人を呼んだのは
確かめるためなんでしょ？
to check on them, right?
絶園の魔法使いが誰なのか｡
(哲馬)はぁ～｡ そこにいるだろ｡
To see who the mage of Exodus really is?
He's back there.
(山本)こっちの
頼りない方じゃなくて…｡
Not that sorry excuse.
The one who has the heart of Exodus.
(山本)絶園の心を持つ者を｡
(葉風)幽霊？
(村下)はあ｡➡
A ghost?
Yes.
A child supposedly saw a pale ghost near the shrine last night.
ゆうべ 神社で
白い顔の幽霊を見たとぬかす➡
子供がおりましてな｡
なるほど｡
I see...
それが この村に入り込んだ者だ
という線は確かにあるな｡
I suppose it could indeed have been somebody sneaking into the village.
It would be easy to mistake someone hiding in the darkness of night for a ghost.
闇夜に紛れる姿で
潜む者がおれば➡
幽霊と見間違えても
おかしくもない｡
ちょうどいい｡
(村下)はっ？
We can use it to our advantage.
You may spread that rumor.
そのうわさも広めてかまわん｡
Then the children will not wander where they shouldn't.
さすれば 子供らが恐れて➡
余計な場所に行かぬであろう｡
As you wish.
(村下)承知｡
(葉風)少し我らも探ってみるか｡➡
Shall we conduct our own investigation?
ついでに 村を案内する｡
I'll show you the village, as well.
Shouldn't you rest for a little while?
(村下)しかし
ゆっくりできぬのですか？➡
You have just returned home.
ようやく
お帰りになったというのに｡
I apologize, but we're still in the middle of our journey.
(葉風)すまぬ｡
故あって まだ旅の途中だ｡
As you already know,
知ってのとおり
はじまりの樹によって➡
the Tree of Genesis has drastically changed the world.
世界は大きく変えられた｡
Right now, I feel as though
今は 左門の意見にも
耳を傾けねばならぬと思っている｡
I should at least listen to Samon's wishes.
(裏村下)姫様 随分と分別が…｡
You sound much more reasonable.
Er, I mean you've become even more refined.
あっ いえ ご立派になられた｡
It's a man.
男だね｡
おぼこは 男で変わるからのう｡
Women change because of men.
(２人)ひゃははははっ！
That's not it! He's...
ち… 違う！ この者は…｡
Aren't you too old to be so embarrassed?
てれる年でもなかろうに｡
姫様の年には わしら➡
At your age, we bore swarms of children left and right.
子供は うじゃうじゃと｡
うじゃうじゃと｡
Left and right...
Ch... Chi... Chil...
(老婆たち)ひゃははははっ！
こっ ここっ こっ…｡
Miss Hakaze, you're walking a bit fast.
葉風さん ちょっと速いですよ｡
情けないぞ｡ もっと昔は… ほら➡
How pitiful.
Long ago...
Look.
あれに滑車を掛けて
ぶら下がって渡ったと聞くぞ｡
I heard they'd cross the river by using a pulley on that.
Whoa. No way.
うわっ… 無理でしょ｡
しかたない｡
Looks like I have no choice.
≪いかん！ スキンシップなど
してしまったら➡
Wait!
If I touch him, my feelings will grow even more.
また気持ちが
高ぶってしまうではないか≫
Oh, thank yo—
あっ すいません｡ えっ？
I'm moving ahead.
やはり先に行く｡
えっ？ うっ… うわ～！
立派な神社ですね｡
This is a very impressive shrine.
The spy probably came here to look for ancient documents.
(葉風)おそらく ここに古文書でも
探しに来たのであろう｡➡
また来る可能性は高い｡
It's quite possible he will return.
Could something here explain the origin of the Tree of Genesis?
はじまりの樹の由来とかを
示すものがあったりするんですか？
No,
いや 記録は ほとんど
形としては残っておらず➡
most of our records aren't left in physical form,
but are passed down through word of mouth.
口伝で伝わっているのみだ｡
(山本)じゃあ
諜報員が この村を探っても➡
So you're saying that even if a spy came here,
何も奪えるものは
ないということ？
there would be nothing for them to take?
この村に住む者たちが
どのような力を持つか➡
The powers possessed by the villagers here
are quite evident.
もちろん知っているはずだ｡
あっ…｡
(哲馬)絶園の魔法使いが
現れた今となっては➡
Unfortunately, the existence of the mage of Exodus
当然 そこに目が行くだろう｡
is drawing attention to the existence of magic.
And since everyone in this village can use magic, well...
ここは 魔法が使える者ばかりが
住む村なのだ｡
Man, that felt great!
いや～ 気持ちよかった～｡➡
総檜っていうんですか？➡
Was that a full Japanese cypress bath?
The bath at Mr. Samon's place is fantastic!
なんか立派でしたよ
左門さん家のお風呂｡
You're way too relaxed. This is not a Japanese inn.
(山本)くつろぎすぎ｡
旅館じゃないのよ｡
(夏村)すでに姫様より
お触れが出ているそうです｡➡
Apparently, the princess has already issued a warning.
She has said that no one, under any circumstances, should use magic for a while.
いかなる事情があろうと➡
当分 魔法を使うことを
一切 禁ずると｡
Not surprising, but she does move fast.
(哲馬)
さすがに 手を打ってきたか｡➡
We must hide the fact that this is a village of mages at all costs.
ここが 魔法使いの村であることが
知られるのだけは避けねばな｡➡
ほかには？
(羽村)あっ さっき 僕も➡
What else?
Oh, someone at the mansion told me a weird story.
屋敷の人に
変な話 聞きましたけど｡
(山本)変な話？
この村で幽霊を見た子がいるって｡
A weird story?
They said a child in this village saw a ghost.
じゃあ 最悪 諜報員が
見つからなくてもいいってこと？
So in the worst-case scenario,
we just give up looking for the spy?
As long as they don't witness us using magic, it's fine.
魔法さえ見られなければ
それでかまわぬ｡
それこそ
幽霊話で終われば害もない｡
I don't mind if this ends up as a ghost story.
幽霊か…｡
でも なんか おかしいですね➡
A ghost, huh?
But it's funny, isn't it?
魔法使いの子供たちが
幽霊を怖がるって｡
That mage children would be afraid of ghosts?
Really?
そうか？
哲馬など 怖がりだったぞ｡
Tetsuma was quite a scaredy-cat.
よく脅かしては
ちびらせたものだ｡
I often made him pee his pants in fear.
I think I may have figured out why he doesn't like Miss Hakaze much.
≪あの人が 葉風さんに
微妙な敵対心を持ってる理由が➡
分かったような…≫
Is something the matter?
どうかしたのか？
あっ… その～ じゃあ➡
Ah, so you're not afraid of ghosts?
葉風さんは平気なんですか？
当たり前だ｡
Of course.
The Princess of Genesis doesn't fear ghosts...
はじまりの樹の姫宮が
幽霊などと…｡
≪いや
ここは 怖がってみせた方が➡
But if I appeared scared here, would I look cuter?
かわいげがあるというものか？≫
Wait, wait, what in the world am I thinking at a time like this?
≪待て待て 何を考えている！≫
≪この期に及んで…≫
あっ… どうかしましたか？
Is something wrong?
U-Um, well...
いや…
んんっ！ その～ あれだな➡
You also only believe in things that you can see, correct?
お前も 目に見えるものしか
信じぬたちであろう｡
そう見えますか？
違うのか？
Is that how I appear?
Am I wrong?
｢『見える』とやらは
ぼくの知ったことではない｣｡
Seems, madam! Nay it is; I know not "seems."
何？
｢ハムレット｣のセリフです｡
What?
It's a quote from Hamlet.
あの話の発端も幽霊なんですよ｡
That story is also about a ghost.
毒殺された王様が➡
The king is poisoned and killed,
then, as a ghost, he appears before Hamlet to demand revenge.
その息子であるハムレットに
真相を伝え 復讐を迫る｡
本当に亡霊が見えたのかと
母親に問われて…｡
His mother asks him if he really saw a ghost...
((バン！))
((バン！ バン！))
((ご不満のようですね))
You seem troubled.
Well, you said that I'm the scariest person you know.
((そりゃ いちばん怖い人って
言われたからね))
I'm just wondering if that's how I seem to people.
((｢見えるですって？
いや 事実そうなのだ｡➡
Seems, madam!
Nay it is;
I know not "seems."
『見える』とやらは
ぼくの知ったことではない｣))
((はぁ… また｢ハムレット｣))
Hamlet again?
I imagine you're the type
(愛花)((たぶん
吉野さんなら 亡霊が見えても➡
who'd say you hadn't seen a ghost even if you had.
見えないと言い張りそうですね))
((そもそも 僕は信じてないし))
I don't believe in them to begin with.
((だんだん 真広に似て
つまらない人になってきましたね➡
You're slowly becoming a boring person, like Mahiro.
不合理なものは認めない))
You won't accept irrational things.
((バン！))
((バン！ バン！))
(愛花)
((ぼんやりと悲しいですね➡
It's a little sad, isn't it?
咲いては消えて))
They bloom, then disappear.
(愛花)((去っていった人に
霊でもいいから会いたい…➡
You'd like to see someone who'd passed on, even as a ghost.
そんな気持ちも否定しますか？))
Would you deny those feelings, as well?
((う～ん…))
(愛花)((例えば➡
For example,
私の霊ならどうですか？))
what if it were my ghost?
≫(村人)見つかったか!?
≫(村人)いや まだ｡
Did you find her?
No, not yet.
一体 いつから…｡
夕方に 一人で出かけたっきり｡➡
When was the last time you saw her?
Not since she left by herself, around dusk.
Anyway, let's keep looking.
とにかく ほかを捜そう｡
どうした！
What is the matter?
姫様 大変です！➡
It's not good, Princess.
Sana's gone missing!
佐奈が行方知れずに！
((復讐を望み 破滅する者の話が➡
Is a story about someone desiring revenge so much that they destroy themselves really that interesting?
それほど面白いか？))
((意外だな｡
読んだことあるのか？))
Well, that's unexpected. You've read it?
I saw the play with my girlfriend when we were in high school.
((高校生のとき
彼女と一緒に舞台で見た))
((お前にも
高校のときがあったのか？))
So you actually attended high school?
((人をなんだと思っている))
What do you think I am?
Hamlet's mistake was
((ハムレットの間違いはな➡
亡霊なんて いもしないもんを
真に受けたからだ))
that he believed in something that doesn't exist, like a ghost.
((理屈に合わないもんを
信じた時点で➡
The second he believed in something irrational,
破滅は決まってたんだよ))
he was doomed.
((お前は 死者の声を
霊魂を信じないのか？))
Do you not believe in voices of the dead or in spirits?
Those are just delusions imagined by the living.
((そいつは
生きている人間の気の迷いだ))
((死んだら それまでだよ))
Once you're dead, that's it.
((死人は生き返らない))
The dead don't return,
((こちらの願いも聞きはしない))
nor do they hear our wishes.
((全部 幻だよ))
It's all an illusion.
((言い忘れてたこと
言えなかったことを➡
Things you forgot to say, things you couldn't say...
幽霊にでも聞いてほしくて
そんな夢を見るのさ))
They want ghosts to hear them, so they dream them up.
((あるいは 自分の願望を
幽霊の形で見るのかもな))
It's also possible that people imagine their desires as ghosts.
(哲馬)そいつは
不破真広の言うとおりだな｡
Fuwa Mahiro is correct in this respect.
幽霊など
ただの気の迷いにすぎん｡
Ghosts are mere delusions.
随分 きっぱり否定するのね｡
You say that with such conviction.
案外 苦手だったりとか？
バ… バカ言え！
Could it be you're scared of them?
Don't be silly!
いずれにせよ
子供が見たとかいう幽霊は➡
Anyway, it makes more sense to assume
忍び込んだ諜報員と考えた方が
筋が通る｡
that the ghost the child believes to have seen is the spy.
当たってみる価値はありそうだ｡
It'd be good to investigate.
(山本)
だけど 面白いわね 真広君｡➡
But Mahiro is rather interesting.
He denies the existence of ghosts, but loves Hamlet.
亡霊を否定しておきながら
｢ハムレット｣が好きだというのも｡
((俺が好きなわけじゃない))
I don't actually like it, anyway.
((愛花のヤツが やたら
引用してやがったんだよ))
It's just that Aika used to quote it all the time.
≪妹を失った兄と彼女の恋人が➡
It's a story where, in the end, a woman's lover and her brother,
最後に殺し合う話だぞ≫
mourning over his sister's loss, fight to the death.
≪それを兄の前で？≫
That brother would be you...
((｢ハムレット｣だけじゃねぇ))
((ん？))
It wasn't only Hamlet.
She would quote from this thing, too.
((たまには こいつからも
引用してやがったよ))
(夏村)((｢テンペスト｣？))
((そいつの内容は知らねぇか？))
The Tempest?
You don't know that one?
((最後には すべてを許し➡
In the end, everything is forgiven,
皆が自由に
幸せになって終わる話さ))
and everyone ends up happy and free.
｢ハムレット｣と｢テンペスト｣？
Hamlet and The Tempest?
They are both tales of revenge,
同じ復讐話だが
結末は まったく異なる｡
but the endings are exactly opposite.
(哲馬)見ろ！
(山本)あっ｡
Look!
(葉風)佐奈～！
(村下)佐奈や～！➡
Sana!
佐奈～！
≪ガサガサッ
Fire... The shrine is on fire!
(裏村下)火だ！
神社から 火が上がっている！
あっ！ 吊り橋が！
The suspension bridge!
They're using rather forceful tactics
魔法の存在を
確かめるためとはいえ➡
随分と強引な手を使ってきたな｡
じゃあ 諜報員が？
to prove the existence of magic.
Then the spy...
待て！
うまくいけば見極められる➡
Wait!
This is the perfect opportunity to learn
滝川吉野が絶園の魔法使いか否か｡
whether Takigawa Yoshino is indeed a mage of Exodus.
吉野君も
疑いをかけられて気の毒ね｡➡
It's too bad we only suspect Yoshino of being one,
considering we know the other one is.
もう一人が あんな調子だから…｡
いや～ 何度入っても
気持ちがいいなぁ｡
Man, this feels great every single time.
(村下)ん？ おい 佐奈だ！
(２人)はっ！
Look! It's Sana!
(葉風)佐奈！
Sana!
Why did she come here?
なぜ こんな所に来ていたのだ！
幽霊のうわさは聞いていたはずだ｡
She should have heard about the ghost.
聞いていたから来たのかも｡
何？
She may have come here because she heard about the ghost.
What?
分かるような気がします｡
I think I understand.
とにかく助けねば！ やむをえん｡
Anyway, we must save her!
There's no other choice.
(村下)
姫様 魔法は御法度と ご自分で…｡
Princess, you were the one who ordered not to use magic!
魔法を使わせるのが
向こうの狙いだ｡
The guy is trying to force you into using it!
If we don't stop it, the fire will spread into the forest!
放っておけば
林にまで 火が移るぞ！
カメラを どこかに仕掛けてる
可能性だってある！
It's also possible that there's a hidden camera somewhere!
Then what should we do?!
ならば どうする!?
魔法が使えなければ➡
Without magic, there are only children and old folks here!
ここにいるのは
ただの子供と老人だけだ！
(葉風)吉野！
Yoshino!
ふん！ んん～…｡
くっ！
(葉風)何をする気だ！
What are you doing?
この鎖をロープに掛けて渡れば…｡
バカを言え！ 危険だぞ！
If I slide over the rope using this chain...
Don't be ridiculous. That's too dangerous!
I'll separate him from Sana and lead him away!
佐奈ちゃんと あいつを切り離して
僕が引き付けます！
吉野！
Yoshino!
≪もし自分の兄の幽霊なら…➡
She thought she could see her brother's ghost...
そう願って ここに来たんだ≫
That's why she came.
≪たとえ幽霊だろうと
会いたくて≫
Even if he were a ghost, she wanted to see him.
吉野！
Yoshino!
Yoshino...
吉野君が…｡
冷静なあの男には珍しい｡
That's rare, considering he's usually quite composed.
だが すべて
計算ずくだとすれば？
But this could all be part of his plan.
でも あんな命懸けのまねが
できると思う？
You think he would do something that risky?
What's so risky about it?
どこが命懸けだ｡
彼が魔具を持っているのを
忘れたのか？
Have you forgotten he has talismans?
林の奥に逃げろ！
Run into the forest!
ガッ！
がはっ！
ふん！
うっ！ くっ… うお～！
Yoshino!
吉野！
はっ…｡
(葉風)聞き届けよ！
Hear me!
やはり使った！
いや 滝川吉野が使わせた｡
She used it!
No, Takigawa Yoshino made her use it.
Once an innocent girl realizes her sensuality...
(老婆)うぶな娘が色気づいたら…｡
(老婆)手に負えんがの｡
...she becomes impossible to handle.
(老婆たち)ひゃははははっ！
待て！ うっ…｡
Wait!
いい働きだったよ
こちらにとってはな｡
That turned out well.
For us, anyway.
大丈夫か!?
ちょっと足をくじいたかなって…｡
Are you all right?!
I just twisted my ankle a little.
気付かれたみたいですね
魔法のこと｡
It looks like they found out about magic.
That's not...
そんなことは…｡
That's not what I care about right now!
そんなことは…➡
どうでもいい！
えっ？
(葉風)心配… したのだぞ…｡
I was so worried.
葉風さん｡
Miss Hakaze...
(山本)この成り行きすべてが➡
Are you saying that
everything happened this way because of the mage of Exodus?
絶園の魔法使いの
お芝居だったというの？
(哲馬)自分のために
はじまりの樹の姫宮が➡
The Princess of Genesis has begun to disregard
理を 犯すことさえ
いとわなくなる｡➡
the Tree of Genesis's logic, all for his sake.
そんな力を持つ者が
絶園の魔法使い以外 どこにいる？
Who else would have that kind of power, besides the mage of Exodus?
でも たぶん 葉風さんは➡
But I think Miss Hakaze sees Yoshino in a completely different way.
あなたと まったく異なった
吉野君を見ている｡
あんたには どう見えてるんだ？
Well, how do you see it?
分からない 見えている何を
信じればいいのか…｡
I don't know.
I don't know what I'm supposed to believe.
(葉風)≪ああ ダメだ≫
It's no use.
≪たとえ
やましさに押し潰されようと➡
Even if the guilt is crushing me,
私は…➡
I'm...
私は吉野が 好きだ≫
I'm in love with Yoshino.
(山本)自国のって…｡
The spy...
この国の諜報機関から
送り込まれたっていうの？
Are you saying that a national agency is behind that?
I admit it was rather unexpected,
(早河)正直 予想外だったが➡
鎖部の村と魔法の関係が
知られたことは➡
but it may be to our advantage that the Kusaribe village
かえって好都合となるかもしれん｡
[TEL](山本)どういうこと？
and its connection to magic have been found out.
What do you mean?
(早河)こちらの握っているカードを
有効に使える機会が増えそうだ｡
It looks like we'll have more opportunities to use our cards effectively.
Sounds like you'll be reinstated soon.
(山本)
あなたの復帰も早まりそうね｡
[TEL](早河)そう願いたいものだが｡
One can only hope.
こちらもね
面白いものが見つかったかも｡
I may have found something interesting myself.
[TEL](早河)面白いもの？
Something interesting?
(山本)はじまりの樹や絶園の樹が
なんであるか➡
Something that may be a key
その手がかりになるようなものが｡
to learning why the Trees of Genesis and Exodus exist.
kimi no utatta hanauta ga
The song you hummed
boku no hanauta to kasanatta
and the song I hummed were the same
yoku aru koto kamoshirenai kedo
Maybe this is not so rare,
tokubetsu datte omoitainda
but I'd like to believe it's special
tokidoki fuan ni mo naru kara
Sometimes everyone feels anxious
tsui mata sagashite shimaundayo
and we wind up seeking it again
me ni mienai ito no youna
Like an invisible string,
futari wo tsuyoku tsunagi au mono
it is what connects us two
tatoe hoka no dare ga waratte mo
Even if others laugh about that,
boku wa tsuyoku shinjiteru kara
I believe it exists,
ima mo zutto zutto negatte iruyo
and so I keep on wishing even now
futari de iru mirai wo
for a future where we are together
mae wo muite aruite yuku yo
I will look ahead and walk
hitori kiri janai kara
because I am not alone
itsu no hi ka kimi to hora unmei datta ne tte
I hope we can one day laugh and say "Hey, it was destiny"
issho ni waraeru to ii na
Wouldn't that be nice?
(左門)
高校生にとっての彼女とは➡
The girlfriend of a high school student
同じ学校の生徒｡
is his classmate.
(葉風)これは何か!? ラブコメか!?
What is this? A love comedy?
(左門)ならば 人妻はどうだ？
Then how about a married woman?
(愛花)あなたまで
腐れ外道認定されることでしょう｡
Even you will become a certified "scumbag."
それはねぇだろ｡
That's harsh.
I must say that I'm curious about hand-made shaved ice.
(愛花)私も 人間かき氷に
興味がないでもありません｡
マリンスノー… か｡
Marine snow, huh?
Episode 17
Marine Snow